Mss.Ms.Coll.56
American Philosophical Society
- XIX. Plane Table Maps, 1950-1986; 2.0 box 2 boxes (oversize); 119 items (Box OS-2, OS-3)
  - 45. 1955 January 5. Villa Mercy, Maryland.
    "Pasture Basin at Water Tower, Villa Mercy" [near Bethesda, Maryland]; Wolman, Leopold.
  - 46. 1955 March 4. Watts Branch, Maryland
    "Watts Branch, Point Bar"; Leopold, Wolman.
  - 47. 1955 July 30. Pole Creek, Wyoming
    Side 1: "Pole Creek near Little Half Moon Lake (near Pinedale, Wyoming) below gage house".
    Side 2: "Sketch of same reach shown on other side of this sheet".
  - 48. 1955 August 8. Porcupine Creek, Colorado
    "Porcupine Creek above Gould, Colorado, reach on Gould Till"; [L.] Leopold, Wolman, B. Leopold.
  - 49. 1955 August 9. Michigan River, Colorado
    "North Fork Michigan River above Gould, Colorado"; Leopold, Wolman, B. Leopold.
  - 50. 1955 August 10. Silver Creek, Colorado
    [Map 1] "Silver Creek 2 miles above camp, on Silver Creek till"; Leopold, Wolman. [Map 2] "1 cfs Tributary to Silver Creek".
  - 51. 1956 February 21, March 15; 1958 May. Watts Branch, Villa Mercy, Maryland, 1956 February 21; 1956 March 15; 1958 May
    Side 1: "Watts Branch net to iron stakes"; Leopold, Wolman; 1956 February 21. Inset: "Sketch of downsteam bend"; with tracing paper overlay in black and red ink, noted, “Correction by R.H. 5/58”.
    Side 2: "Sisters Creek Watersheds, Villa Mercy near Bethesda, Maryland; Leopold, Wolman. 1956 March 15.
  - 52. 1956 April 4; 1955 August 2. Pole Creek, Wyoming, 1955 August 2; 1956 April 4
    "Hoot Owl Reach, Pole Creek near Pinedale, Wyoming"; 1955 August 2; "high terrace surveyed 1956 July 4"; with pencil sketch of owl.
  - 53. 1956 June 29. Blackrock Creek, Wyoming
    "Blackrock Creek 3 1/2 miles from Togwotee Pass, Wyoming, headwaters of Buffalo fork"; [L.] Leopold, Wolman, B. Leopold; map wrapped in acetate.
  - 54. 1957 August 18-19. Wind River, Du Noir Creek, Wyoming
    Side 1: "Dumb Cowboy Reach of Wind River near Sheridan Guard Station above Dubois, Wyoming"; L. Leopold, B. Leopold. 1957 August 18.
    Side 2: "Cutoff on Du Noir Creek near Dubois, Wyoming"; L. Leopold, B. Leopold, Brush. 1957 August 19.
  - 55. 1957 August 20. Buffalo Fork, Wyoming
    "Natural Cutoff on Buffalo Fork near Black Rock RS."; Leopold, Wolman, Brush.
  - 56. 1958 July 10. Arroyo de los Frijoles, New Mexico
    "Arroyo de los Frijoles below Buckman Road, 4 miles NW of Santa Fe, New Mexico"; Leopold, Miller. [Two reaches on this map.] Annotation, "2 sheets" (see map no. [57] for Sheet no. 2).
  - 57. 1958 July 10. Arroyo de los Frijoles, New Mexico
    "Arroyo Frijoles cont’d"; "Sheet 2". [See map no. [56] for Sheet [1].]
  - 58. 1958 August 6, 26. Canada Ancha, Arroyo de los Frijoles, New Mexico
    Side 1: "Canada Ancha at USGS BM 6227 in Sect. 4 T17N R8E". 1958 August 6.
    Side 2: "Locust Tree Reach, Arroyo de los Frijoles, 1 mile E of W edge, Santa Fe Grant and 1.38 mile S of N edge of Grant"; Leopold, Marsh; “Land owned by Mr. Rodriguez”. 1958 August 26.
  - 59. 1958 August 27. Arroyo de los Frijoles, New Mexico
    "Sand Plug Reach of Arroyo de los Frijoles"; Leopold, Marsh.
  - 60. 1958 August 28. Arroyo de los Frijoles, New Mexico
    "Arroyo de los Frijoles from Project Reach to Sand Plug"; Leopold, Marsh.
  - 61. 1958 November 4. Arroyo de los Frijoles, New Mexico
    "Arroyo de los Frijoles below Buckman Road 4 miles NW of Santa Fe, New Mexico; lower section"; Myrick, Rickard.
  - 62. 1958 November 4. Arroyo de los Frijoles, New Mexico
    "Arroyo de los Frijoles below Buckman Road 4 miles NW of Santa Fe, New Mexico; upper section"; Myrick, Rickard.
  - 63. 1958 November 5. Arroyo de los Frijoles, New Mexico
    "Locust Tree Reach, Arroyo de los Frijoles, 1 mile E of W fork, Santa Fe Grant and 1.38 mile S of N edge of Grant"; Myrick, Rickard.
  - 64. 1958 November 12-13. Arroyo de los Frijoles, New Mexico
    "Sand Plug Reach of Arroyo de los Frijoles"; Myrick, Rickard; with references to map of 1958 August 27.
  - 65. 1959 February 3, March 25. Seneca Creek, Maryland, 1959 February 3; 1959 March 25
    "Seneca Creek near Dawsonville, Maryland"; Leopold, Myrick; notes on verso.
  - 66. 1959 March 26. Seneca Creek, Maryland
    "Seneca Creek near Dawsonville below Gage Reach"; Leopold, Myrick.
  - 67. 1959 March 31. Seneca Creek, Maryland
    Side 1: "Seneca Creek near Dawsonville, Sheet 3"; Leopold, Myrick.
    Side 2: "Seneca Creek, Sheet 4".
  - 68. 1959 April 3. Watts Branch, Maryland
    "Watts Branch at Viers Pasture, near Rockville, Maryland"; Leopold, Myrick.
  - 69. 1959 April 6. Watts Branch, Maryland
  - 70. 1959 April 9. Seneca Creek, Maryland
    Sides 1 and 2: "Profiles down right and left flood plain of Seneca Creek at Dawsonville"; Leopold, Miller.
  - 71. 1959 June 9-14. Baldwin Creek, Wyoming
    Side 1: "Night-work Reach of Baldwin Creek near Lander, Wyoming"; Leopold, Myrick; in pencil and colored pencils depicting surface standing waves and surface float paths; with pencil sketch of recorder and tree.
    Side 2: “Cont’d from opposite side”.
    Side 2: "Cont'd from opposite side".
  - 72. 1959 June 13. Baldwin Creek, Wyoming
    "The Jury Rig Bend of Baldwin Creek near Lander, Wyoming"; Leopold, Myrick; in pencil and colored pencils, depicting standing waves and paths of surface floats.
  - 73. 1959 June 14-15. Baldwin Creek, Wyoming
    "Baldwin Creek"; Leopold, Myrick.
  - 74. 1959 July 20, 1961 July 13. Slope Wash, tributary to Arroyo de los Frijoles, New Mexico
    "Slope Wash Tributary of Frijoles Arroyo 3 miles NW of Santa Fe, New Mexico"; 1959 July 20; Leopold, Miller, Myrick. Map continued 1961 July 13; Leopold, P.S.
  - 75. 1959 August 19. Old Mill Creek, Delaware
    "Tidal Meander, Old Mill Creek near Lewes, Delaware"; Leopold, Myrick; with pencil sketch of canoeist holding stadia rod.
  - 76. 1959 August 22. Clear Creek, Wyoming
    "Clear Creek 2 miles below Claremont, Wyoming"; Leopold, Wolman.
  - 77. 1960 April 20. Potomac River, Virginia
    "Wrecked Recorder Tidal Stream, Potomac River 1 mi. S of Alexandria, Virginia"; Bagnold, Myrick, Leopold.
  - 78. 1960 August 23. Big Sweat and Little Sweat Dams, tributary to Arroyo de los Frijoles, New Mexico
    "Big Sweat and Little Sweat Dams, tributary to Arroyo Frijoles on right bank at Main Project Reach near Santa Fe, New Mexico"; Miller, Myrick.
  - 79. 1960 September 15. Watts Branch, Maryland
    "Watts Branch near Rockville, Maryland, Highway 28 to gaging station"; Leopold, Myrick.
  - 80. 1961 March 23. Seneca Creek, Maryland
    "Gravel Bar, Seneca Creek near Dawsonville,Maryland"; Leopold, Leeson.
  - 81. 1961 June 6, 1962 June 1. Popo Agie River, Wyoming
    "Popo Agie River near Hudson, Wyoming"; Leopold, Myrick, Jopling; 1961 June 6. Also in red pencil: “Red resurvey June 1, 1962, Emmett, Myrick, LBL”.
  - 82. 1961 July 14. Coyote Creek Arroyo, La Frente Arroyo, New Mexico
    "Earth Dams at Las Dos (Santa Fe, New Mexico) on Coyote Creek and La Frente Arroyos, tributaries to Las Dos Arroyo"; Leopold, Nace, Sparks.
  - 83. 1961 July 14, 1962 July 7; 1963. Coyote Creek Arroyo, La Frente Arroyo, New Mexico
    "Earth Dams at Las Dos near Santa Fe, New Mexico, on Coyote Creek and La Frente Arroyos, tributaries to Los [sic] Dos Arroyo"; topography, 1961 July 14; cross-sections, 1962 July 7; “1963--The River Boys”; in green and red ink on mylar.
  - 84. 1961 July 18. Coyote Creek Arroyo, New Mexico
    "Las Dos: Gully Headcut, Arroyo Coyote Creek"; Leopold, Miller.
  - 85. 1961 December 4, 1962 April 5. Watts Branch, Maryland
    "Watts Branch near Rockville, Maryland in Vier’s Pasture below Highway 28." [Map 1] 1961 December 4; Leopold, Emmett. [Map 2] 1962 April 5; Emmett, Leopold.
  - 86. 1962 May 17. Tidal stream, Alexandria, Virginia.
    "Tidal Stream, Alexandria, Virginia"; Langbein, Emmett, Leopold
  - 87. 1962 June 2. Last Day Gully, Wyoming
    "Vigil Network Survey 'Last Day Gully', 1/2 mile from Joyful Reach of Popo Agie River and about 2 miles from Hudson, Wyoming"; Myrick, Emmett, Leopold.
  - 88. 1962 July 7. Coyote Creek Arroyo, New Mexico
    "Headcut, Coyote Creek Arroyo"; 1962 July 7, overlay of map of 1961 July 18; Myrick, Emmett, Leopold, M. Smith; on mylar.
  - 89. 1962 July 8. Arroyo Falta, New Mexico
    "Arroyo Falta near Las Dos"; Leopold, Smith; on mylar.
  - 90. 1962 July 26-27. Hasta Luego Draw, Montana
    "Hasta Luego Draw near Billings, Montana"; Emmett, Smith; with pencil sketch of “GSA” truck and rain cloud; on mylar.
  - 91. 1962 July 29. Neardark Gully, Powder River, Wyoming
    "Neardark Gully near Arvada, Wyoming"; Emmett; pen and ink on mylar; sheet smaller than normal.
  - 92. 1962 July 29. Neardark Gully, Powder River, Wyoming
    "Neardark Gully, Powder River, 1 mile E of Arvada Road Jct."; Emmett, Smith; on mylar.
  - 93. 1962 July 31. Gullies near Arvada, Wyoming
    "Gullies Graded to Middle Terrace near Arvada, Wyoming"; Emmett, Smith [2 maps, “Gully No. 1”, “Gully No. 2”]; on mylar.
  - 94. 1962 August 8. Last Day Gully, Wyoming
    "Last Day Gully, II"; Emmett, Smith; with pencilled sketches of rattlesnake forms depicting “Twin Rattlesnake Headcut”.
  - 95. 1962 August 8. Last Day Gully, Wyoming
    "Last Day Gully (cont’d), Sheet 2 of 2"; Emmett, Smith.
  - 96. 1962 August 10. Forsaken Gully, Wyoming
    "Forsaken Gully near Moneta, Wyoming"; Emmett, Smith; includes “Dick Hedley’s study area for slope wash”.
  - 97. 1962 August 12. Drainage Area No. 2 near Lance Creek, Wyoming
    "Drainage Area No. 2 near Lance Creek, Wyoming, 2.0 miles by road to post office at Lance Creek Village, Wyoming"; Emmett, Smith.
  - 98. 1962 August 13. Typical section no. 3 near Lance Creek, Wyoming
    "Typical Section No. 3 near Lance Creek, Wyoming (survey for retreat of high terrace), 8.10 miles by road to post office at Lance Creek Village"; Emmett, Smith.
  - 99. 1962 August 14. Drainage Area No. 1 near Lance Creek, Wyoming
    "Drainage Area No. 1 near Lance Creek, Wyoming"; Emmett, Smith.
  - 100. 1963 June 18. Wind River, Wyoming
    "Dumb Cowboy Reach of Wind River near Sheridan Guard Station"; Leopold, Emmett, Myrick, Slaymaker.
  - 101. 1963 June 18. Wind River, Wyoming
    "Straight Reach of Dumb Cowboy Reach, ± 1/2 mile above Wind"; Leopold, Emmett, Myrick,Slaymaker.
  - 102. 1963 July 16. Dickerson Park, Wyoming
    "No Grub Hillslope, Dickerson Park, above Ft. Washakie, Wyoming"; Leopold.
  - 103. 1963 August 10. Yucca Thorn Dam Site, Mesa Verde National Park, Colorado
    "Yucca Thorn Dam Site above Long House at Mesa Verde National Park, Colorado, Vigil Network Survey,USGS"; Emmett, Leopold.
  - 104. 1963 August 12-13. Aching Shoulder Vigil Network site near Mitten Rock, New Mexico
    "Sketch map of Aching Shoulder Vigil Network site near Mitten Rock, New Mexico"; Emmett.
  - 105. 1963 August 12. Basketmaker 3 Ruins near MItten Rock, New Mexico
    "Topography of Basketmaker 3 Ruins, Aching Shoulder Vigil Network Site near Mitten Rock, New Mexico"; Emmett, B. Leopold; ruin structures mapped in red ink.
  - 106. 1964 June 22. Pole Creek, Wyoming
    "Pole Creek at Clark’s Ranch near Pinedale, Wyoming"; Leopold, Emmett; in pencil and colored pencils depicting riffling and substrates; with folded tracing paper overlay extending stream banks.
  - 107. 1965 June 19. Colorado River at Badger Creek, Marble Canyon, Arizona
    "Marble Canyon, Colorado River, Badger Creek"; Leopold.
  - 108. 1965 June 20. Colorado River at Royal Arches, Marble Canyon, Arizona
    "Marble Canyon, Colorado River at Royal Arches"; Leopold.
  - 109. 1967 June 9. Green River at Old Cabin Bend, Utah
    "Green River at Old Cabin Bend ± 11 mi. south of Green River, Utah" [Sheet 1]; Leopold, Gillen, Allen.
  - 110. 1967 June 9. Green River at Old Cabin Bend, Utah
    "Green River at Old Cabin Bend ± 11 mi. south of Green River, Utah"; “Sheet 2 of 2”.
  - 111. 1970 January 28. Canalized Colorado River [Arizona-California] above Needles, California
    "Canalized Colorado River above Needles, Arizona [sic]"; Leopold, Johnson, Allen, Myers; notes on verso. “Notes are in Book 42, 1969.”
  - 112. 1970 January 29. Canalized Colorado River [Arizona-California] above Needles, California
    "Canalized Colorado River above Needles, Arizona [sic]"; on mylar.
  - 113. 1970 May 20. East Fork River, Wyoming
    "Project Reach, East Fork River near Boulder, Wyoming"; Leopold; with numerous pen and ink water-surface elevations.
  - 114. 1971 June 7. [James] Noble property parcel, Wyoming
    "A Parcel of Noble Property"; Leopold, Dunn; on heavy paper stock. [Noted on map: Fence between SW 1/4 and SE 1/4 of NW 1/4 Sec 13 T34N R110W.]
  - 115. 1975 July 18. Horse Creek, Wyoming
    "Horse Creek near Daniel (Koch Ranch)"; Leopold, Carroll.
  - 116. 1979 June 26. Beeline Ditch, Pearson Pasture [Colorado?]
    "Beeline Ditch in Pearson Pasture"; Muir, Champion, Leopold; on reinforced board manufactured by Glassoloid Corp.
  - 117. 1980 January 18. Jewel Creek, Tilden Park, East Bay, San Francisco Bay Area, California
    "Jewel Creek, Tilden Park"; Leopold; two pieces of heavy paper stock, taped; verso of both sheets include perspective sketches and plans of unidentified small buildings.
  - 118. 1980 August 13. Red Bluff Hill, California
    "Red Bluff Hill"; Leopold, Nelson.
  - 119. 1986 August 2; 1989 July 12; 1990 July 3, 27. Ditch Creek, Wyoming
    Side 1: "Ditch Creek at Teton Science School, Kelly, Wyoming"; Leopold. 1986 August 2.
    Side 2: "Ditch Creek"; 1986 August 2. “Addition of BM 1, 2, 4 X Sections July 12 1989”; with pebble counts noted separately, 1990 July 3 and 1990 July 27.
- Oversize Material, 9.0 folders
  Oversize, folded material located in folders throughout the collection have been removed from their original folders and placed in the Oversize collection. Place markers have been placed inside the original folders; removed items are accompanied by original-location notations.
  - Folder 0. [Material from Series I.] (Folder [Zero])
  - Folder 1. [Material from Series II.] (Folder 1)
  - Folder 2. [Material from Series II.] (Folder 2)
  - Folder 3. [Material from Series VIII, Subseries 1.] (Folder 3)
  - Folder 4. [Material from Series VIII, Subseries 1.] (Folder 4)
  - Folder 5. [Material from Series VIII, Subseries 1.] (Folder 5)
  - Folder 6. [Material from Series VIII, Subseries 3, 6; Series IX.] (Folder 6)
  - Folder 7. [Material from Series XIII.] (Folder 7)
  - Folder 8. [Material from Series XI.] (Folder 8)
- Extra-Oversize Material, 6.0 folders
  Extra-Oversize, folded material located in folders throughout the collection have been removed from their original folders and placed in the Extra-Oversize collection. Place markers have been placed inside the original folders; removed items are accompanied by original-location notations. In a few cases, the entire contents of folders have been moved; in which cases the original-location folders are kept as place markers and annotated accordingly.
  - Folder 1. [Material from Series VIII, Subseries 1: Items 1-6.] (Folder 1)
  - Folder 2. [Material from Series VIII, Subseries 1: Arroyo de los Frijoles map.] (Folder 2)
  - Folder 3. [Material from Series VIII, Subseries 1: Map set labelled, "Topographic Sheets nr. Berkeley".] (Folder 3)
  - Folder 4. [Material from Series VIII, Subseries 3: Colorado River-Grand Canyon Plan & Profile (1921).] (Folder 4)
    Colorado River. "Plan and Profile, Lees Ferry, Ariz. to Black Canyon, Ariz.-Nev. and Virgin River, Nev."; Sheets C, I, P-U only; not annotated. Colorado River sheets only. Map plans and river profiles surveyed by C. H. Birdseye et al. during 1923 U.S. Geological Survey expedition on Colorado River through Grand Canyon to identify dam sites.
  - Folder 5. [Material from Series VIII, Subseries 3: Green River-Colorado River (Lake Powell) maps.] (Folder 5)
  - Folder 6. [Material from Series IX and Series XIII.] (Folder 6)